# DANIELE AUTIZI

Stockholm, Sweden

daniele.autizi@gmail.com www.danieleautizi.com

#### **PROFILE**

A confident, versatile and enthusiastic Software Engineer, focused on JAVA/PYTHON Web Development, with an in-depth understanding of back-end to front-end usage and full software lifecycle development, predominantly within media and editorial environments.

Acknowledged as a highly reliable and committed professional I am able to develop and maintain strong working relationships at all levels of seniority, and in turn motivate and support teams towards delivering results within specified deadlines.

Furthermore, I am highly motivated, with excellent problem solving skills and can work well under pressure, working on my own initiative and as part of a team. I have an excellent work ethic and excel in fast paced, high pressure working environments.

## **KEY KNOWLEDGE, SKILLS & EXPERTISE**

- Occupation-based Highly focused software developer professional, experienced in JAVA/PYTHON web development, qualified in computer science engineering. Experienced in Agile Development process for diverse requirements.
- **Tenacity** Possesses the determination to deliver the technical support skills that are required by the business.
- Leadership Strong leadership and management skills, promoting drive and business focus.
- **Teamwork** Able to motivate and encourage others to achieve personal and business goals, using strong mediation skills to gain positive results.
- **Communication** Relays information clearly and concisely as project manager so peers understand what action they need to take regarding all aspects of various software projects.
- **Customer service** Attention to detail, showing client focus thereby achieving maximum customer satisfaction.
- **Dedication** Believes in loyalty towards employer, demonstrating excellent time management skills and gaining trust and respect within the workplace.
- Language skills Italian and English.
- Technical skills
  - o Languages: Java, Python, Node.is, SQL, Html, CSS, JSON, XML, UML, PL/SQL;
  - o Scripting: Javascript, ¡Query, Yui, Unix Scripting;
  - o Databases: MySQL, SyBase, MS SQL, Informix;
  - NoSQL: MongoDB, Apache SolR search server;
  - o Build Tools: Ant. Maven:
  - Versioning: Github, SVN, CVS;
  - Operating Systems: Linux(Fedora, Ubuntu), Windows 98/2000/XP/Vista/7, Mac OS X;
  - Web Server: Apache Tomcat 5.0/5.5/6.0/7.0/8.0;
  - Libraries and frameworks:
    - Java: Spring Framework, Spring MVC, Struts 2, Hibernate Framework, Jasper Reports, Apache Velocity, Apache Url-Rewrite, Junit, Selenium test;
    - Python: Django;

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Atex (Stockholm - Sweden) Software Engineer Jun 2015 - present

Responsibilities

• Application Specialist Polopoly. Developing solutions based on Polopoly CMS for large media industry sites across the globe. Currently involved in professional service for the Canadian media giant called "Bell Media".

L'Espresso Editorial Group (Rome - Italy)

Jan 2013 - May 2015

Software Engineer Responsibilities

• Developing Java software within the editorial industry (including radio and tv media).

- Project Manager, designer and developer for the new multi-brand project "Restaurant". Restaurant web based solution has been designed considering marketing requirements, SEO compliance, performance and developed using standard technologies such as Spring MVC, Apache Solr as NoSql search server, MySql, jQuery, RestFul WS and introducing Apache Velocity instead of jsp and JSON instead of XML for new WS.
- Worked in all aspects of developing Java web-based new multi-brand product called "Tempo Libero" (Free Time), including technical support and training for journalists about CMS backend side. Involved in maintenance and development of new features for the group main project www.repubblica.it from internal proprietary CMS to frontend new sections.
- Currently project owner of www.ilmiolibro.it developed with Django, ws RestFul in Node.js and MongoDB as NoSQL DB.

# Cogetech (Rome - Italy) Java Software Engineer

Jan 2012 - Dec 2012

- Responsibilities
  - Managing and testing betting and gambling projects to completion, via web (J2EE) and stand-alone applications.
  - Involved in development of different web-based projects as www.iziplay.it and web console for betting shop.
  - Initially worked in the first version of Web Console was implement in Java. Worked implementing the users-profile rules module, which was a complex task used to build dynamically customized user window starting by assigned role. Web Console is actually used by all shops in agreement with Cogetech to manage better accounts.
  - Discussed the design and architecture of the product "E-Wallet" for a new module. Working in "E-Wallet" helped me to understand and acknowledge concepts for accuracy within credit card certification, money computation and transfer.
  - Besides the design and development of features, also engage marketing and Business unit to give technical support and

## Freelance Java Analyst and Developer (Rieti/Rome/Terni - Italy) Responsibilities

Jan 2011 - Dec 2011

- Collecting and analysing functional requirements to develop project entitled "School Manager" currently used in all schools of Rieti. Continuos support and maintenance for this J2EE project developed with Struts2, Spring and MySQL db through stored procedure queries.
- Project experience includes specification writing and testing.

## **ESE Engineering (Viterbo - Italy)**

Jan 2010 - Dec 2010

# **Operative Director**

Responsibilities

- IT Work Director on photovoltaic plants located in Monalto di Castro and Canino.
- Discussed technology and solutions for monitoring green-power production inside and outside plant. Site Manager, liaising and interfacing between customers and building companies.
- Meeting reporting deadlines and providing technical support.

## L'Espresso Editorial Group (Rome - Italy)

Jan 2008 - Dec 2009

## **Software Engineer**

Responsibilities

Developing and testing projects within publishing industry, including apache url rewrite, spring, fast engine search and editorial CMS.

# Melograno Data Services (Rome - Italy)

Mar 2007 - Dec 2007

#### **Software Engineer/Analyst**

Responsibilities

- Defining, design and developing software projects for national health sector.
- Reverse engineering (First Aid) of stand-alone application ("Pronto Soccorso").
- Designing and analysing new web application ("Nuovo Pronto Soccorso") with final testing case.

#### PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS & EDUCATION

#### **University Rome**

MSc Computer Science Engineering (pending)

**BSc Computer Science Engineering** 

#### **Technical Institute for Commercial Surveyors**

AutoCad Design